They were here
他們來過了
Ozpin, they were here!
Ozpin，他們來過了！
We're very much aware of that, thank you, James
這個我們很清楚，多謝了，James
Fantastic, you're aware
太棒了，清楚就好
Now are we going to do something about it or should we just stay the course and continue to ignore what's right in front of us?
那現在我們是該採取些對策，還是該堅持繼續無視眼前的事態？
Come in
進來
Ah, sorry it took so long
抱歉，現在才來
Someone accidentally hit all the buttons on the elevator on the way up here
正好有人把電梯裡向上的所有按鈕都按了
It wasn't me
不是我幹的
Thank you for coming, Ruby. How are you feeling?
謝謝你能過來，Ruby，感覺如何？
Okay, I guess
還行..吧
I'd feel better if my bad guy catching record wasn't O for three
如果我抓壞蛋的記錄不是三次撲空我會更好受
Okay, so that's the tone we're going for, got it
好吧，這氣氛得用這種態度，懂了
Ruby
Ruby
I feel it's appropriate to let you know that I think what you did last night is exactly what being a Huntress is all about
我想讓你知道，我認為你昨晚的行為體現的正是獵人應當具備的品質
You recognized a threat, you took action, and you did the very best you could
你認清了威脅，採取了行動，並竭盡所能做到最好
Thank you, sir
謝謝您
Now, the General here has already informed us of the events that..transpired last night
雖然將軍已經詳細告訴了我們昨晚..發生的事
But now that you've rested, we were wondering if you had anything to add
但既然你休息好了，我們想知道你是否還有其它信息
Was anyone else with her? Did she look familiar to you at all?
有人跟她一起嗎？你覺得她眼熟嗎？
I..I dont' know
我..不知道
She was wearing a mask, and she never said anything to me
她帶了個面具，而且對我什麼也沒說
But I know she fought with glass, I don't think that was her Semblance, though
我知道她用玻璃戰鬥，但我想那不是她的外像力
Her clothing lit up whenever she attacked
她攻擊時衣服就會亮起來
Save for the glass, That sounds like the women I fought the night we met Ruby
除了玻璃，感覺就像遇見Ruby那晚跟我戰鬥過的女人
Embedding dust into clothing is an age-old technique. It could've been anyone
把塵晶織入衣服是個古老的技術，誰都有可能
Wait..
等等..
You think this girl's connected with Tochwick and the White Fang?
你們認為這女孩跟Tochwick和白牙有聯繫？
It's possible
是有可能
But we still lack the required evidence to link the two together
但我們依然缺乏所需的證據來關聯這兩者
Actually, I..I think I remember her saying something about a hideout, or something..
其實，我想我還記得她說了些關於藏身之處的東西..
..in the Southeast. Just outside the kingdom
..東南邊，就在王國外邊
Interesting
有意思
I thought you said the intruder never..
你不是說入侵者什麼也沒..
Thank you for your cooperation, Ruby
感謝你的配合，Ruby
Why don't you go and spend some time with your team? You have a big day ahead of you
去跟你的隊員們待一會兒吧？接下來這天會很忙的
Anytime!
當然！
And Miss Rose
而且Rose小姐
Please try and be..
請你盡量..
..discreet about this matter
..謹慎對待這件事
Yes, sir
遵命
What happened?!
發生什麼了！？
Uh..well,um, hehe..aha~
呃..這個嘛，唉..呵呵~
Well there we have it
既然有線索了
We send as many troops as we can to the Southeast
我們盡量多派部隊去東南邊
Find out exactly what's going on and eradicate any forces that stand in our way
弄清具體情況，殲滅所有抵抗力量
Why must your answer to everything involve a triumphant display of military bravado?
為什麼你處理任何事都要炫耀一番武力？
You treat every situation like it's a contest of measuring..
你把任何情況都當成軍力競爭..
Glynda
Glynda
Well, he does
他就是嘛
She's right
她沒說錯
As much as I too would love to end this situation once and for all
我也很想一勞永逸地解決這件事，但..
We must remember that this may go beyond Vale, beyond Beacon
必須記住使用武力可能就不局限在溪谷，不局限在信標了
And if this truly is part of some master plan for which we know not the final move
如果這真的只是我們不知道的某個大計劃中的一部分
We musn't be so bold
就不能魯莽行事
Nor can we risk the spread of panic
也不可冒險散佈恐慌
I have served you faithfully for years
我老老實實幫你辦事這麼多年了
But if you mean to tell me that your plan is to really hold the defenses and wait..
如果你的意思就是你準備固守防線然後傻等..
It is not!
不是傻等！
You're a general, James
你是個將軍啊，James
So tell me, when you prepare to go to war, which do you send in first?
告訴我，你若準備開戰，會先派什麼部隊？
The flag bearer..
是扛旗的工兵..
or the scouts?
還是偵察部隊？
That was a risky move
你太冒險了
No, I think you handled it well
沒，我覺得你處理得很好
I hope so
希望如此
I'm sure everything will be alright, Ruby
我保證不會有事的，Ruby
Oh, I know what will cheer you up!
噢，我知道怎麼讓你打起精神！
What's that?
那是啥？
I don't know yet, Dad sent it to us, I thought we can open it together
我還不知道，老爹寄來的，我們可以一起打開
Oh, something from home!
噢，家裡寄來的！
Zwei!
Zwei！
He sent a dog?!
他寄來一條狗！？
In the mail?
用郵寄的！？
Oh, he does stuff like this all the time
哦，他成天幹這種事
Stop it..I missed you~
快停下..想死你了
Your father or your dog?
你是說你爹還是你的狗？
Are you telling me that this mangy..
你是想說這髒兮兮的..
drooling..
流口水的..
mutt..
蠢東西..
is going to to live with us forever?!
要一直跟我們在一起！？
Oh yes he is,  yes he is! >v<
噢，當然可以，必須啊！>v<
Oh, he's adorable >w<
噢，萌死了 >w<
>w<
噢>w<
Please keep it away from my belongings
請別讓它靠近我的東西
Would all first year students please report to the amphitheater
請所有一年級學生到競技場大廳報到
Well, we can't exactly leave him here while we're gone for a week
我們要離開一周，也不能就把他丟在這兒啊
Look, there's a letter
瞧，還有封信
Dear girls, I've got to leave the island for a few days, so I'm sending Zwei to you to take care of
寶貝女兒們，我得離開島上幾天，所以把Zwei寄給你們照顧
Enclosed is all the food you should need
需要的所有食物都在信封裡
Love you both, Tai Yang
我愛你們，Tai Yang
What is he supposed to do with that?
他要怎麼開罐頭？
Welp, that settles it
嘛，這個能解決
Come on girls, Zwei will be here when we get back
走吧妹子們，回來時Zwei還會健在的
Oh, I'll miss you so much, we're going to be best friends, I can't wait to see you again, I need such.. >w<
噢，我會很想你的，我們會成為最好的朋友，簡直不能等啊，我要.. >w<
Quiet, quiet please
安靜，請安靜
Professor Ozpin would like to share a few words before we begin
在開始之前Ozpin教授有一點兒話要說
Today we stand together, united
今天我們團結地站在一起
Mistral
寒風
Atlas
阿特拉斯
Vacuo
維基亞
Vale
溪谷
The four kingdoms of Remnant
樹不子的四大王國
On this day, nearly eighty years ago, the largest war in recorded history came to an end
幾乎就在八十年前的今天，有史記載的最大規模的戰爭剛結束
It was a war of ignorance, of greed, and of oppression
一場充滿無知、貪婪、壓迫的戰爭
A war that was about much more than where borders fell or who traded with who
一場比領土紛爭、確定貿易夥伴重要得多的戰爭
but about the very idea of individualism itself
這場戰爭關乎個人主義本身
We fought for countless reasons, one of which being the destruction of all forms of art and self expression
我們為無數理由而戰，其中一條就是上頭要廢除所有藝術形式和自我表達能力
And as you are well aware that was something many could not stand for
正如你們所知，這一條讓很多人無法忍受
As a result, those who oppose this tyranny began naming their children after one of the core aspects of art itself:
結果那些反對暴政的人就開始用藝術本身的核心要素之一給他們的孩子取名：
color
顏色
It was their way to demonstrate that not only would they refuse to tolerate this oppression
他們用這種方式表示：不但自己拒絕忍受這種壓迫
but neither were the generations to come!
下一代也絕不能忍！
And it was a trend that is held to this very day
而這個取名傾向一直持續至今
We encourage individuality, expressionism, and unity, through diversity
我們通過多樣性來倡導個性、自我表達、團結精神
As I have said, today we stand together, united
如我所言，今天我們團結地站在一起
But this bond cannot exist without effort
但這種羈絆不通過努力就無法實現
Which is why today while the rest of the world celebrates peace
這就是為何當世界各地都在歡慶和平時
Huntsmen and Huntresses will work to uphold it
獵人們要努力工作維護和平
As first year students, you will be tasked with shadowing a professional Huntsman or Huntress on a mission
作為一年級學生，你的工作就是跟隨一名職業獵人進行一項任務
Some of you may be taken out of the Kingdom for several days
你們中一些人可能會被帶出王國好幾天
Others may work within the walls for the rest of the week
搜救任務 失蹤的商人 第一區 護送任務 護送一家人抵達溪谷 第二區 邊界防禦 修城牆
But no matter which path you choose
不過不論你選哪類任務
Remember to be safe
銘記安全第一
Remember your training
回想起你的訓練
And remember to do your very best
而且牢記要竭盡全力
This is perfect! All we have to do is shadow a Huntsman working in the southeast!
32個贊！我們只需要跟著一名去東南邊執行任務的獵人就行了！
Yeah! We'll follow him around by day and give him the slip at night
對！我們白天跟著他，晚上就開溜
Let's check Search and Destroy
那就找找「搜尋與殲滅」任務
Here we go, Quadrant 5 needs Grimm cleared out
就這個，第五區需要清除戮獸
Well, it's in the southeast
嗯，是在東南邊
Sounds perfect
貌似不錯
Wonderful!
好極了！
Any other ideas?
有別的辦法嗎？
We mail ourselves there
我們把自己寄過去
Well, that's one option
嗯，這也是種辦法
Unfortunately, we determined that the concentration of Grimm was too extreme for first year students
很不幸，我們認為戮獸太集中不適合一年級學生
It seems that particular region is rather popular
貌似某些特定區域挺有人氣
In fact, I have the sneaking suspicion that the four of you will make your way there no matter which job you choose
事實上，我暗中懷疑你們四個無論選哪個活都會跑去那裡
Whatever makes you say that?
你為什麼會這麼想？
I'm still curious as to how you all found yourselves at the docks last semester
我依然很好奇上學期你們四人怎麼全在碼頭
I'm interested to know how you really learned about a hideout in the Southeast
我對你真正獲取東南方藏身之處情報的渠道很感興趣
And I certainly wonder why witnesses reported seeing robots and rose petals in a dance club some time ago
而且我更奇怪為什麼之前有目擊者聲稱在一個夜總會看見了機器人和玫瑰花瓣
Ah..um..eh, well..
呃..唔..嗯，這個嘛..
I doubt I'll ever find the exact answers I'm looking for
我懷疑我根本找不到想要的答案
So, how about this?
乾脆，這樣吧？
Instead of waiting for you all to break the rules, why don't we just bend them?
與其等著你們違規，不如我們把規則修改一下？
We won't let you down.Thank you, professor
不會讓你失望的，謝謝教授
Do not thank me for this
這個不用謝我
Teamwork and persistence have carried you far
團隊合作與頑強毅力讓你們走了這麼遠
But you must understand
但你們必須明白
The things that await you beyond the protection of the Kingdom will not care
王國保護範圍外等著你們的那些玩意兒不會管這些
Stay close to your Huntsman at all times
時刻緊跟帶你們的獵人
And do exactly as he says
他說什麼就做什麼
He will be leading you on this mission
他會帶你們做這個任務
And he can have you sent back to Beacon, if he finds your skills to be unsatisfactory
而且如果他不滿意你的能力，也可以把你送回信標
Good luck
好運
That wasn't exactly uplifting
完全不像在給我們打氣
But it's the truth
但這就是真相
It's gonna be tough, but I know we can do it
會很艱苦，但我知道我們能行
Hey, Team CFVY is back!
喂，CFVY隊回來了！
Velvet? Are you okay?
Velvet？還好吧？
I'm fine, I had Yatsuhashi to look out for me
沒事，Yatsuhashi會照顧我
Your mission was supposed to end a week ago! What happened?
你們的任務一周前就該結束了！發生什麼意外了？
Um..nothing happens
沒有意外
It was just..
只是..
..there was just so many
..數量太多了
Oh, but don't worry
哦，不過別擔心
You first years are just shadowing Huntsmen, so you should be fine
你們一年級只要跟著獵人們就行，應該沒問題
Right
正♂解
I should go, be safe, okay
我要走了，注意安全哦
We can do this
我們能行的
We've never backed down before, and we're not going to start now
我們從未打過退堂鼓，現在也不準備開始打
Right
沒錯
Besides, it won't only be us out there, we'll be fighting alongside a genuine Huntsman!
更何況又不是只有我們，我們會跟真正的獵人並肩作戰！
Yeah!
就是啊！
Why, hello girls
哇，少女們好呀
Who's ready to fight for their lives?
準備好為生存而戰了？
BRB
BRB
This SUB is presented by Baidu RWBY Bar Creator: sbz_kid
本字幕由百度RWBY吧提供 片源/翻譯/時間軸/特效/後期：sbz_kid